Tyler James

behance.net/tjjames230 | github.com/tjjames230

(312) 721-5597 | tjjames230@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Creative designer with 7+ years of experience in UX/UI design, web development, print advertisement and marketing. Skilled at exploring and implementing design theories using a variety of platforms. Excited to work in an environment where I will contribute and continue to learn from other professionals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Website Graphic Designer | Ecreativeworks | St. Louis Park, MN | Oct. 2022 - Present

- Lead designer for all website clients
- Designed prototypes that clients could interact with and give feedback
- Interviewed clients to research what user flows worked best for their customers
- Organized bi-weekly meetings to review design style

Communications Specialist | Hennepin Ave UMC | Minneapolis, MN | Jan. 2022 - Oct. 2022

- Used Wordpress to create and make updates to website pages
- Utilized Figma to create low and high-fidelity designs for website redesign
- Created a user flow and site map based on member feedback for website redesign

Website Designer | ARI Network Services | Duluth, MN | Jul. 2018 - Apr. 2021

- Interviewed clients to create wireframes
- Used Figma to create low and high-fidelity designs for new websites
- Managed 70+ projects at any given time
- Completed changes within a CMS website editor

Graphic Artist | Gannett Inc. | Des Moines, IA | Jan. 2017 - Jul. 2018

- Designed print ads using InDesign and Photoshop for newspaper companies
- Designed digital ads using Photoshop and Illustrator

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Design Tools: Figma, Affinity, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

Developer Skills: HTML, CSS/SCSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, Git, Webpack

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

B.A. in Graphic Design, English | Augustana College | May 2016